GDPR C2P DPA

GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION ADDENDUM TO THE GENERAL TERMSAND CONDITIONS(GDPR Article 28 Controller to Processor terms)

Last updated: December 7, 2021

By using the Services, Supplier Technology, and/or entering into any Order Form, Company agrees to the SupplierGeneral Data Protection Regulation Addendum to the Terms and Conditions (the “C2P Addendum”). Supplier andCompany are each a “Party” and collectively the “Parties.”

This C2P Addendum is an integral part of the Terms and Conditions. Any words or terms not otherwise defined inthis Addendum have the same meaning as in the Terms and Conditions. In the event of a conflict betweendefinitions in the Terms and Conditions and this Addendum, the definitions within this Addendum control.

1. Definitions.

(a) “Company” means the entity(ies) as defined in the Order Form.(b) “Company Personal Data” means Personal Data controlled by Company and disclosed to RakutenAdvertising (or collected by Rakuten Advertising on behalf of Company) in circumstances where RakutenAdvertising is instructed by Company to act as the Processor of such Personal Data and as further set outat Schedule 1 hereto.(c) “Data Protection Law(s)” means all worldwide data protection and privacy laws and regulations applicableto the Company Personal Data, including, where applicable, EU/UK Data Protection Law and the SwissDPA.(d) "EU/UK Data Protection Law" means: (i) Regulation 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of theCouncil on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the freemovement of such data (General Data Protection Regulation) (the "EU GDPR"); (ii) the EU GDPR as savedinto United Kingdom law by virtue of section 3 of the United Kingdom's European Union (Withdrawal) Act2018 (the "UK GDPR"); (iii) the EU e-Privacy Directive (Directive 2002/58/EC); and (iv) any and allapplicable national data protection laws made under, pursuant to or that apply in conjunction with any of(i), (ii) or (iii); in each case as may be amended or superseded from time to time;(e) “European Territories” means together the European Economic Area (‘EEA”), United Kingdom, andSwitzerland.(f) “Personal Data,” “Process/Processing,” “Controller,” “Processor,” “Data Subject” and “SupervisoryAuthority” shall have the same meanings given to them in EU/UK Data Protection Law.(g) “Rakuten Advertising” means the following Rakuten Advertising entities: Rakuten Marketing LLCorganized and existing under the laws of Delaware, USA successor to LinkShare Corporation (“RM UnitedStates”), Rakuten Marketing Europe Limited successor to LinkShare Limited (“RM Europe”), RakutenMarketing Australia Pty Limited successor to LinkShare Australia Pty Ltd (“RM Australia”), or RakutenBrazil Holdings, LLC successor to LinkShare Brazil Holdings, LLC (“RM Brazil”).(h) "Restricted Transfer" means: (i) where the EU GDPR applies, a transfer of Company Personal Data fromthe European Economic Area to a country outside of the European Economic Area which is not subject toan adequacy determination by the European Commission; (ii) where the UK GDPR applies, a transfer ofCompany Personal Data from the United Kingdom to any other country which is not based on adequacyregulations pursuant to Section 17A of the United Kingdom Data Protection Act 2018; and (iii) where theSwiss DPA applies, a transfer of Company Personal Data from Switzerland to any other country which isnot determined to provide adequate protection for Personal Data by the Federal Data Protection andInformation Commission or Federal Council (as applicable).(i) "Standard Contractual Clauses" means: (i) where the EU GDPR or Swiss DPA applies, the contractual

GDPR C2P DPA

clauses annexed to the European Commission's Implementing Decision 2021/914 of 4 June 2021 onstandard contractual clauses for the transfer of personal data to third countries pursuant to Regulation (EU)2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council ("EU SCCs"); and (ii) where the UK GDPR applies,standard data protection clauses adopted pursuant to or permitted under Article 46 of the UK GDPR ("UKSCCs").(j) “Sub-processor” means a third party engaged directly by Rakuten Advertising to Process CompanyPersonal Data on Rakuten Advertising’s behalf.(k) "Swiss DPA" means the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection 1992 (including as amended orsuperseded).

2. Role of the Parties.

In order to receive the Services under the Terms and Conditions, as set out in the Order Form, Company disclosesCompany Personal Data to Rakuten Advertising (or Rakuten Advertising collects Company Personal Data on behalfof Company). For the purposes of this DPA, Company is the Controller of the Company Personal Data and RakutenAdvertising is the Processor of the Company Personal Data.

3. Company’s Controller Obligations.

In its role as Controller of the Company Personal Data, Company shall:(i) comply at all times with Data Protection Law(s);(ii) ensure that it has all necessary rights (including, where required, consent of Data Subjects) todisclose Company Personal Data to Rakuten Advertising for Rakuten Advertising to Process theCompany Personal Data under the Terms and Conditions (or for Rakuten Advertising to collectCompany Personal Data on behalf of Company), including Rakuten Advertising’s use of cookies andtracking technologies, as set out in Schedule 1 to this DPA; and(iii) fulfil its transparency obligations and shall ensure that the Company Sites that Company promotesthrough its use of the Services display a privacy policy which complies with Data Protection Lawsand which includes information regarding Rakuten Advertising’s processing of the CompanyPersonal Data for online advertising as anticipated under this DPA.

4. Rakuten Advertising’s Processor Obligations.

(a) The nature, purpose, subject matter, duration of Rakuten Advertising’s Processing of the CompanyPersonal Data, and the types of Company Personal Data Processed and the categories of Data Subjectsare as set out in Schedule 1 to this DPA and Rakuten Advertising shall only process the Company PersonalData in accordance with this DPA.(b) In its role as Processor of the Company Personal Data, Rakuten Advertising shall:(i) Process the Company Personal Data in accordance with the Company’s written instructions as setout in the Terms and Conditions (including Order Forms) and this DPA. If Rakuten Advertising isrequired by law to Process or disclose the Company Personal Data for any other purpose, it shallnotify Company as soon as the law permits it to do so;(ii) inform Company if it believes the Company’s instructions infringe the Data Protection Laws or anyother applicable law;(iii) comply with applicable obligations of Processors as required under EU/UK Data Protection Law;(iv) not subcontract any processing of the Company Personal Data to a third party Sub-processor withoutthe prior written consent of Company, which consent, where Company is a Processor, shall reflectthe instructions of its controller. Notwithstanding this, Company consents to Rakuten Advertising

GDPR C2P DPA

engaging third party Sub-processors from an agreed list to process Company Personal Data providedthat Rakuten Advertising: (i) provides at least ten (10) business days' prior notice of the engagementof any subprocessor to be added to the list or the termination of any subprocessor to be removedfrom the list (including details of the processing it performs or will perform), which may be given byposting details of such engagement or termination at the following URL:https://rakutenadvertising.com/legal-notices/subprocessors (ii) procures that all Sub-Processors aresubject to written terms that protect the Company Personal Data, in substance, to the same standardprovided by the terms of this DPA; and (iii) remains fully liable for any breach of this DPA that iscaused by an act, error or omission of its Sub-processor. Company may object to RakutenAdvertising appointment of a new Sub-Processor on reasonable grounds relating to the protection ofthe Company Personal Data, by notifying Rakuten Advertising in writing within the relevant ten (10)business day notice period. Upon receipt of such objection from Company, Rakuten Advertising shallmake a commercially reasonable change to the Sub-Processor or to the Services to avoid using suchSub-Processor for the processing of Company Personal Data. If Rakuten Advertising is unable tomake such change within a reasonable period of time, which shall not exceed thirty days, Companymay terminate those services which cannot be provided by Rakuten Advertising without the use ofthe objected-to Sub-Processor by providing written notice to Rakuten Advertising;(v) have in place and maintain throughout the term appropriate technical and organizational securitymeasures to protect Company Personal Data against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss,alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. The appropriate technical and organizational securitymeasures by Rakuten Advertising and its third parties shall be commensurate with the nature ofCompany Personal Data to be protected and with regard to the state of the art and cost ofimplementation, the nature, scope, context and purposes of the Processing;(vi) ensure that all Rakuten Advertising employees are informed of the confidential nature of theCompany Personal Data and bound by a legal obligation of confidentiality;(vii) notify Company without undue delay after it becomes aware of a Personal Data breach withinRakuten Advertising’s environment or under its control and which affects Company Personal Data;(viii) taking into account the nature and use of Company Personal Data in providing Services (and to theextent the Company does not otherwise have access to the relevant information), reasonably assistCompany in complying with its obligations as Controller under EU/UK Data Protection Law in relationto Data Subject rights, Personal Data breach notifications and data protection impact assessments.(ix) upon Company’s written request at reasonable intervals, and subject to the confidentiality obligationsset forth in the Terms and Conditions, make available to Company that is not a competitor of RakutenAdvertising (or Customer’s independent, third-party auditor that is not a competitor of RakutenAdvertising) a copy of Rakuten Advertising’s then most recent published third-party audits orcertifications, as applicable.(x) on termination or expiry of the Terms and Conditions, securely destroy the Company Personal Dataand certify to Company that it has done so, unless legal or regulatory obligations prevent it fromdestroying all or part of the Company Personal Data. In that case, Rakuten Advertising shall use itsreasonable measures to protect confidentiality of the Company Personal Data and will not activelyfurther Process such data.

5. International Data Transfers.

The Parties hereby acknowledge and agree that in providing the Services, conducting the Actions and otherwisefulfilling Order Forms, Personal Data may be transferred from European Territories to the United States or otherterritory(ies) whose level of protection for Personal Data differs from that of the European Territories. WhereCompany makes a Restricted Transfer to Rakuten Advertising for the purposes of the Services, such transfer shallbe subject to the appropriate Standard Contractual Clauses, as follows:

GDPR C2P DPA

(a) in relation to Company Personal Data that is protected by the EU GDPR, the EU SCCs will apply completedas follows:(i) Module Two will apply;(ii) in Clause 7, the optional docking clause will apply;(iii) in Clause 9, Option 2 will apply, and the time period for prior notice of subprocessorchanges shall be as set out in Clause 4(b)(iv) of this DPA;(iv) in Clause 11, the optional language will not apply;(v) in Clause 17, Option 1 will apply, and the EU SCCs will be governed the laws ofLuxembourg;(vi) in Clause 18(b), disputes shall be resolved before the courts of Luxembourg;(vii) Annex I of the EU SCCs shall be deemed completed with the information set out inSchedule 1 to this DPA; and(viii) Annex II of the EU SCCs shall be deemed completed with the information set out inSchedule 2 to this DPA; and(b) in relation to Company Personal Data that is protected by the UK GDPR, the UK SCCs will apply completedas follows:(i) For so long as it is lawfully permitted to rely on standard contractual clauses for the transferof Personal Data to processors set out in the European Commission’s Decision2010/87/EU of 5 February 2010 (“Prior C2P SCCs”) for transfers of Personal Data fromthe United Kingdom, the Prior C2P SCCs shall apply between Company and the RakutenAdvertising entity to which a Restricted Transfer is made on the following basis:(A) Appendix 1 shall be completed with the relevant information set out in Schedule 1to this DPA;(B) Appendix 2 shall be completed with the relevant information set out in Schedule 2to this DPA; and(C) the optional illustrative indemnification Clause will not apply.(ii) Where sub-clause (b)(i) above does not apply, but Company and Rakuten Advertising arelawfully permitted to rely on the EU SCCs for transfers of Personal Data from the UnitedKingdom subject to completion of a “UK Addendum to the EU Standard ContractualClauses” (“ UK Addendum”) issued by the Information Commissioner’s Office unders.119A(1) of the Data Protection Act 2018, then:(A) The EU SCCs, completed as set out above in Clause 5(a) of this DPA shall alsoapply to transfers of Company Personal Data, subject to sub-clause (B) below; and(B) The UK Addendum shall be deemed executed between Company and the RakutenAdvertising entity to which the Restricted Transfer is made, and the EU SCCs shallbe deemed amended as specified by the UK Addendum in respect of the transferof such Company Personal Data;(iii) If neither sub-clause (b)(i) or sub-clause (b)(ii) applies, then Company and RakutenAdvertising shall cooperate in good faith to implement appropriate safeguards for transfersof the relevant Company Personal Data as required or permitted by the UK GDPR withoutundue delay;(c) in relation to Company Personal Data that is protected by the Swiss DPA, the EU SCCs will apply as setout in Clause 5(a) amended as follows:

GDPR C2P DPA

(i) references to ‘Regulation (EU) 2016/679’ in the EU SCCs will be deemed to refer to theSwiss DPA;(ii) references to specific articles of ‘Regulation (EU) 2016/679’ will be deemed replaced withthe equivalent article or section of the Swiss DPA,(iii) references to ‘EU’, ‘Union’ and ‘Member State’ will be deemed replaced with ‘Switzerland’,(iv) references to the ‘competent supervisory authority’ and ‘competent courts’ are replacedwith the ‘Swiss Federal Data Protection Information Commissioner’ and ‘applicable courtsof Switzerland’ (as applicable),(v) in Clause 17, the EU SCCs will be governed by the laws of Switzerland, and(vii) in Clause 18(b), disputes shall be resolved before the competent courts of Switzerland;(d) in the event that any provision of this DPA contradicts, directly or indirectly, the Standard Contractual Clauses,the Standard Contractual Clauses shall prevail.

6. International Transfers – Processor to Controller ("P2C") Restricted Transfers

Where the Rakuten Advertising entity that is party to this C2P Addendum is based in the European Territories andmakes a Restricted Transfer of Company Personal Data on a Processor-to-Controller basis to Company basedoutside the European Territories for the purposes of providing the Services, then, such transfer shall be subject tothe appropriate Standard Contractual Clauses, as follows:a) in relation to Company Personal Data that is protected by the EU GDPR, the EU SCCs will apply completedas follows:

(i) Module Four will apply;(ii) in Clause 7, the optional docking Clause will not apply;(iii) in Clause 11, the optional language will not apply;(iv) in Clause 17, the EU SCCs will be governed by the laws of Luxembourg;(v) in Clause 18(b), disputes shall be resolved before the courts of Luxembourg;(vi) in Annex I, Parts A and B: with the information set out in Schedule 1 to this DPA;

b) in relation to Company Personal Data that is protected by the UK GDPR, the UK SCCs will apply completedas follows:(i) For so long as it is lawfully permitted to rely on the standard contractual clauses for thetransfer of personal data to Controllers set out in the European Commission's Decision2004/915/EC of 27 December 2004 (“Prior C2C SCCs”) for transfers of personal data fromthe United Kingdom, the Prior C2C SCCs shall apply on the following basis:(A) in Clause II (h): the Company (as data importer) and Rakuten Advertising (as dataexporter) choose option (iii);(B) in Annex B: with the information set out in the relevant part of Schedule 1 to thisDPA; and(C) the "Illustrative Commercial Clauses (Optional)" shall be deemed deleted.(ii) Where sub-clause (b)(i) above does not apply, but Rakuten Advertising (as data exporter)and Company (as data importer) are lawfully permitted to rely on the EU SCCs for transfersof Company Personal Data from the United Kingdom subject to completion of a “UKAddendum to the EU Standard Contractual Clauses” (“UK Addendum”) issued by theInformation Commissioner’s Office under s.119A(1) of the Data Protection Act 2018, then:(A) The EU SCCs, completed as set out above in clause 6(a), shall also apply to

GDPR C2P DPA

transfers of such Company Personal Data, subject to sub-clause (B) below;(B) The UK Addendum shall be deemed executed between Rakuten Advertising (asdata exporter) and Company (as data importer), and the EU SCCs shall bedeemed amended as specified by the UK Addendum in respect of the transfer ofsuch Company Personal Data.(iii) If neither sub-clause (b)(i) or sub-clause (b)(ii) applies, then the Rakuten Advertising andCompany shall cooperate in good faith to implement appropriate safeguards for transfersof such Company Personal Data as required or permitted by the UK GDPR without unduedelay.c) in relation to Company Personal Data that is protected by the Swiss DPA, the EU SCCs will apply as setout in Clause 6(a) amended as follows:(i) references to ‘Regulation (EU) 2016/679’ in the EU SCCs will be deemed to referto the Swiss DPA;(ii) references to specific articles of ‘Regulation (EU) 2016/679’ will be deemedreplaced with the equivalent article or section of the Swiss DPA,(iii) references to ‘EU’, ‘Union’ and ‘Member State’ will be deemed replaced with‘Switzerland’,(iv) references to the ‘competent supervisory authority’ and ‘competent courts’ arereplaced with the ‘Swiss Federal Data Protection Information Commissioner’ and‘applicable courts of Switzerland’ (as applicable),(v) in Clause 17, the EU SCCs will be governed by the laws of Switzerland, and(vii) in Clause 18(b), disputes shall be resolved before the competent courts ofSwitzerland;

d) in the event that any provision of this DPA contradicts, directly or indirectly, the Standard ContractualClauses, the Standard Contractual Clauses shall prevail.

7. Indemnification.

Company shall defend, indemnify and hold harmless Rakuten Advertising from and against any and all liabilities,damages, loses, demands claims, suits or judgments resulting from a third party claim arising out of Company’sbreach of its warranties or any of its obligations under this DPA or the Data Protection Laws.

8. Survival.

This DPA shall survive termination or expiration of the Terms and Conditions.

GDPR C2P DPA

SCHEDULE 1TO THE DATA PROCESSING ADDENDUM

RAKUTEN ADVERTISING AS A DATA PROCESSORDATA PROCESSING DESCRIPTION

This Schedule forms part of the DPA and describes the processing that Rakuten Advertising will perform on behalf ofCompany.

A. LIST OF PARTIES

Controller(s) / Data exporter(s): [Identity and contact details of the controller(s) /data exporter(s) and, where applicable, ofits/their data protection officer and/or representative in the European Union]

1. Name: The entity(ies) as defined in the Order Form.

Address: The notice address as defined in the Order Form.

Contact person’s name, position and

contact details:

The contact person’s information as defined in the OrderForm.

Activities relevant to the data transferred

under these Clauses:

Use of the Company Personal Data involves the online and

offline behaviour of end users as they interact withadvertisements promoted through Rakuten Advertising

Signature and date: See above

Role (controller/processor): Controller

Processor(s) / Data importer(s): [Identity and contact details of the processor(s) /data importer(s), including any contact personwith responsibility for data protection]

1. Name: Rakuten Marketing Europe Ltd

Address: 71 Queen Victoria Street, 7th Floor, London, England, EC4V

4AY

Contact person’s name, position andcontact details:

Ra-legalnotices@mail.rakuten.com

Activities relevant to the data transferredunder these Clauses:

Use of the Company Personal Data involves the online and

offline behaviour of end users as they interact withadvertisements promoted through Rakuten Advertising.

Signature and date: See above

Role (controller/processor): Processor

В. DESCRIPTION OF TRANSFERCategories of data subjects whose PersonalData is transferred:

End users who visit Company’s, publishers’ and advertisers’

websites and other internet and mobile enabled platforms

owned or controlled by Company, publishers and advertiserswithin the Rakuten Advertising advertising ecosystem.

Categories of Personal Data transferred: Online identifiers from end users’ device(s), identifiers created

by Rakuten Advertising, Company and customers within theRakuten Advertising advertising ecosystem.

Sensitive data transferred (if applicable) and

applied restrictions or safeguards that fullytake into consideration the nature of the dataand the risks involved, such as for instancestrict purpose limitation, access restrictions(including access only for staff havingfollowed specialised training), keeping arecord of access to the data, restrictions foronward transfers or additional securitymeasures:

N/A

GDPR C2P DPA

The frequency of the transfer (e.g. whether the

data is transferred on a one-off or continuousbasis):

Continuous for the duration of the Terms and Conditions.

Nature of the processing: Commercial purposes including: to trace end users from a

Company’s Site to an advertiser platform to processcommissions, to serve personalized advertisements to endusers, to analyse and create online behavioural advertising,and to prevent fraud.

Purpose(s) of the data transfer and further

processing:

To facilitate the provision of Services by Rakuten Advertising

to Company.

The period for which the Personal Data will beretained, or, if that is not possible, the criteriaused to determine that period:

For Affiliate: up to 49 months for reporting/tracking activities.

For transfers to (sub-) processors, also specifysubject matter, nature and duration of theprocessing:

C. COMPETENT SUPERVISORY AUTHORITYIdentify the competent supervisoryauthority/ies in accordance (e.g. in accordancewith Clause 13 SCCs)

GDPR C2P DPA

Schedule 2Technical and OrganisationalSecurity Measures

Description of the technical and organisational measures implemented by the processor(s) / data importer(s) (including anyrelevant certifications) to ensure an appropriate level of security, taking into account the nature, scope, context and purpose ofthe processing, and the risks for the rights and freedoms of natural persons.

Measure Description

Measures of pseudonymisation and encryption of

Personal DataEncryption is implemented for all target data, bothelectronic transmissions and physical electronic media,prior to sending outside the environment. Sensitivedata is encrypted at rest.Backup Encryption: Active/active data, 256 bit AESencryption, Vault and Console solution for keymanagement and crypto controls. Back-up tapes andother media is decommissioned or destroyed when nolonger in use via NIST standards.

Measures for ensuring ongoing confidentiality, integrity,availability and resilience of processing systems andservices

Rakuten Advertising is subject to the Rakuten GroupRegulations which are an ISO 72001 and NIST 800-53based set of policies and controls that are required forall Rakuten Group companies. Measures for ensuringongoing confidentiality, integrity, availability andresilience of processing systems and services are partof the required RGR controls and Rakuten Advertising isaudited for compliance annually.Measures for ensuring the ability to restore theavailability and access to Personal Data in a timelymanner in the event of a physical or technical incident

By design, there are no single points of failure in theRAN system architecture.

The core platform technology operates in 2geographically separated production parallelenvironments, so in the event of the loss ofone data center, the system fails over to the other. Thefailover process is tested twice annually. Trackingfunctionality operates with 6x redundancy. All databasesare backed up regularly and the system operates withan RTO of 4 hours and RPO of 0.

Processes for regularly testing, assessing andevaluating the effectiveness of technical andorganisational measures in order to ensure the securityof the processing

Rakuten Advertising performs annual privacy and datasecurity/cybersecurity risk assessments, along withcontinuous network and application penetration testingconducted by a dedicated internal team, and annualpenetration testing by an independent third party.Please note that audit and penetration test results areconfidential per security policy and may not be sharedwith external parties.Measures for user identification and authorisation User identification and authorization is handled using aset of custom security components requiring ausername and password to access all necessarysystem functions and reporting capabilities. SSO andMFA options will be made available in 2022.Measures for the protection of data during transmission Data is encrypted in transit using TLS 1.2 with AES 256encryption.Measures for the protection of data during storage Data is processed and stored within the US in one ofour two data centres (we have one on the East Coast inReston, Virginia and one on the West Coast in LasVegas, Nevada. Production data is stored on disks

GDPR C2P DPA

(spinning disk and ssd) in a 3PAR SAN Array managed

by Oracle ASM (Automatic Storage Management)Co-location, with access controls, SVP and Senior TechOps Managers control access list, access to db storageleast privilege model. We use Oracle encryption, filesystem encryption, SSL to protect data and the securityposture of our network perimeter are Routers, Firewalls,Ips, Vlans. Additionally, we use Palo Alto PA5280 withThreat Prevention Subscription. From a vulnerabilitystandpoint, security teams have continuous internal andexternal scanning running, vulnerabilities are given aninternal score that is compared to CVSS. To detect andreport any non-standard patterns, malicious activity andanomalies, Rakuten Advertising leverages anomalydetection software. Finally, we align with NIST, securitystandards and are in the process of getting an externalISO27001 certification.Rakuten Advertising has an information SecurityIncident Response Team and a business continuityprogram via active/standby data centers, with bursts tothe cloud.Data is protected by:Encryption of the data transport channel (TLS 1.2)Encryption of data at rest (AES 256 encryption)Network access controls (Network access through thefirewall requires port level allow listings, or VPN access,wireless network access required VPN/certificate MFAand a registered MAC address)Measures for ensuring physical security of locations atwhich Personal Data are processedProtection of physical access to the building(registration and proper identification required, CCTV inplace, facilities use mantraps, biometric scanning,access lists and government ID required for access)User Authentication (system access follows the principleof least privilege, access rights are audited quarterlyand when employee roles change, privileged accessrequires VP approval and server access is timeboxedusing keys that expire)Recording of actions (actions are logged and stored fora minimum of 3 months, user IDs are tied to each user’sLDAP record and system IDs are assigned to specificcomponents, ID usage is logged and audited to checkfor inappropriate use)Measures for ensuring events logging All log entries must include the following attributes: (a)the time and date of the event, (b) the applicationassociated with the event, (c) the user or processinitiating the event and, if applicable, the subject actedupon, (d) the remote IP address of the initiating user orprocess, (e) success or failure indication, and (f) adetailed description of the event.Information systems that implement multiple logs mustallow correlation of log activity across these logs via aunique ID.All successful and failed login attempts must be logged.All changes to security policy must be logged.All account creations, deletions, and modifications mustbe logged.

GDPR C2P DPA

Granting, revoking, and modification of privileges and

roles must be logged.Information systems must not log confidential andsensitive personal data such as government issued IDs,passwords, etc.All failed access attempts to data, functions andservices must be logged.All password resets, self-service or administrative, mustbe logged.All account lockouts must be logged.Internet exposed information system should write logsto a protected, non-Internet exposed informationsystem.Access to audit logs and audit trails should be logged.Information systems should implement a log analysisfunction that allows searching of security log datafiltered by fields available within the log.Information systems should implement a mechanismthat reports a listing of all user accounts currentlydefined within the system.Information system should implement a mechanism thatreports a listing of all roles and the users assigned tothose roles currently defined within the system.Log timestamps should be set to the CoordinatedUniversal Time (UTC) and Daylight-Saving Time (DST)should not be applied.Logs are stored in a centralized Graylog instance wherethey are protected from unauthorized access ortampering.Measures for ensuring system configuration, includingdefault configurationServer image access is tightly controlled and onlyimages that have been hardened by the RakutenAdvertising TechOps and security operations teams areallowed.Measures for internal IT and IT security governance andmanagementRakuten Advertising's systems are subject to theRakuten Group Regulations which are a set of securitypolicies based on the ISO 27001 and NIST standards.All Rakuten Group companies must comply with theregulations and are subject to annual complianceaudits.Measures for certification/assurance of processes andproductsOur data centers are ISO 27001 certified, SOC2compliant, and follow NIST standards. We are currentlyin the process of getting an external ISO 27001certification.Measures for ensuring data minimisation All Rakuten Advertising systems are audited annually, aprocess which includes a review of all data dictionariesto confirm compliance with regional regulations andcontinued necessity of the data handled by eachsystem.Measures for ensuring data quality All data collected by the integration infrastructure issubject to security, formatting, and syntax validation inthe tracking layer prior to system processing. Onceprocessed, the data in aggregate form undergoesadditional validation processing to ensure that it is notrelated to fraudulent activity.Measures for ensuring limited data retention Please see the section on data retention here:https://go.rakutenadvertising.com/hubfs/Services-Privacy-Policy-English.pdf

GDPR C2P DPA

Also, as noted earlier, all Rakuten Advertising systems

are audited annually, a process which includes a reviewof all data dictionaries to confirm compliance withregional regulations and continued necessity of the datahandled by each system.Measures for ensuring accountability All Rakuten Advertising employees and contractors arerequired to review and confirm acceptance of thecompany’s policies at the start of employment. RakutenAdvertising also provides regular privacy trainings to allemployees. A comprehensive training is delivered atleast once per year that includes test-based certificationof retention of knowledge and employee sign-off/acknowledgement that they will comply with privacypolicies. The trainings cover privacy policy and dataprotection/data security.

Measures for allowing data portability and ensuringerasure]Data is handled in accordance with regional law, andthe company's data handling policies andimplementation of the data handling policies arereviewed at least annually to ensure compliance.Erasure and recycling, or destruction of data handlingmedia is performed per NIST standards.

For transfers to (sub-) processors, also describe the specific technical and organisational measures to be taken bythe (sub-) processor to be able to provide assistance to the controller (and, for transfers from a processor to a sub-processor, to the data exporter).

Measure Description

N/A
